Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and this is our 300th
lesson here at EnglishPod so it's a special
lesson but today we're
talking a little bit about dating.
That's right today
we're going to talk about
dating now in a little
bit of a less conventional
way, a new type of dating, very
modern with using technology.
Using technology
that's right so let's listen
to today's dialogue and
we'll be back in a moment.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
Oh I can't have a date.
Really?
Wow with who?
This girl I've been
chatting with for the
past couple of months, she's really cool
and she's driving over here this weekend.
Wait a minute.
You mean you met her online?
Yeah, I send up for a website
called match.com and it's great.
You fill in all your
details and preferences,
like if you are a smoker or if you have
any pets, then you find people that have
similar characteristics and
you can email them or chat.
That's kind of weird.
What if she's a psycho
or something like that?
It's the same as meeting
people anywhere in dating them.
I'm just tired of going to bars or
being set up for dates by my friends.
I think this is a really cool alternative,
especially if you are a bit shy.
I guess it does seem logical,
I'll have to check it out.
All right, we're back so now
let's take a look at some of these
keywords that we've picked out
for you on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first word is a
word that you're going
to hear English speakers say all the
time, especially if they're Americans.
So cool is our first word.
This guy described this girl
that he is seeing as really cool.
She's really cool.
So what does that mean if I
describe someone as a cool person?
A cool person is someone who you like.
It's a good thing.
So someone who is
cool, I think of as relaxed
and interesting and someone who
maybe had lots of ideas or things to say.
Okay, so if you say that a person is cool,
you're saying that you like that person.
Now, what if you say something
is cool, like Paris is really cool?
Paris is cool.
It's a cool city.
And it's an interesting
city, it's something
that you like, maybe you're trying
to recommend someone to go there.
You can also say that
movie was really cool.
So again, it means you liked it.
Yeah.
Okay.
So talking about dating
this friend, it was a bit
surprised when he said
that he met this girl online.
That's right.
So online, where is this place online?
Cyber space.
All right.
Online means on the internet and we
often use this when describing things.
So English pod is an
online, English learning site.
That's right.
So anything that is in the internet
in cyberspace, you say that is online.
So our website is online or
maybe you have pictures online.
I have many photographs online
or I like to meet people online.
Okay.
So continuing on, we talked about a website
that obviously that's online where you find
people and talking about
preferences, you mentioned that you
can stay to whether you are
a smoker or if you have pets.
So what is a person that's a smoker?
Well, many of you have probably heard the
term to smoke before I smoke cigarettes.
I smoke, but a smoker is a
person who smokes cigarettes.
And so I could say that
I want a non-smoker
if I'm looking for a boyfriend because
I don't want someone who smokes.
But maybe if you do smoke, you
can say I'm looking for a smoker.
Someone who does smoke.
Okay.
So his friend was a little bit
concerned saying, "Well, that's weird.
Why does this grill is a
psycho or something like that?
" All right.
A psycho.
Now, maybe you've
heard of the movie psycho,
but psycho is something
that we use in English
to say that someone is really
crazy, almost scary, crazy.
It comes from the word psychopath, right?
That's right.
And a psychopath is someone
who is crazy, but also very dangerous.
Right.
So when we use this
word, we're describing
someone as being a little bit strange,
or maybe even a little bit dangerous.
That's right.
So we don't want any psychos to
come and talk to us online, right?
That's right.
So he went on to explain how dating is just
the same online as it is offline, and that
he thinks it's a really cool
alternative, even if you're shy.
So something is an alternative if you have
different options, maybe dating by going to
a bar and meeting someone
is what normal people do,
but an alternative to that
would be dating online.
That's right.
I mean, it's another option.
So the word alternative is a
second option, another option.
Right.
For example, if I
want to go have Italian
food tonight, but you
don't want to, I'd say,
hey, Mark, what can you
give me an alternative idea?
That is the other option.
All right.
Great.
So a lot of words in this
very interesting dialogue.
Stay with us.
We'll be right back where we'll
take a look at fluency builder.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
Oh, I can't have a date.
Really?
Wow.
With who?
This girl I've been
chatting with for the
past couple of months, she's really cool
and she's driving over here this weekend.
Wait a minute.
You mean you met her online?
Yeah.
I send up for a website
called match.com and it's great.
You fill in all your
details and preferences,
like if you are a smoker, or if you have
any pets, then you find people that have
similar characteristics and
you can email them or chat.
That's kind of weird.
What if she's a psycho
or something like that?
It's the same as meeting people
anywhere and dating them.
I'm just tired of going to bars or
being set up for dates by my friends.
I think this is a really cool alternative,
especially if you are a bit shy.
I guess it does seem logical.
I'll have to check it out.
All right, we're back and we've
picked out five key phrases for you.
Let's check those out on Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
All right, the first
phrase we've got here is
one that we often use in English spoken
English to talk about seeing our friends.
Okay, so the first person says, "Do you
want to hang out tomorrow to hang out?
" That's right.
So let's hang out.
We never hang out anymore.
What does that mean?
Well, to hang out is it's
hard to define because
you can do many things
when you're hanging out.
But basically, it means
friends being together.
So watching a movie,
listening to music,
chatting, these are all
examples of hanging out.
So maybe if you get
together with your friend,
just sit in the living room
and talk, you're hanging out.
That's right.
Or you could go drive a car
together and you're hanging out.
You're talking.
So to hang out is to be
social, is to talk to your friends.
To spend time together.
And you said, "Wait, oh, I
can't because I have a date.
" Okay.
So a date is a romantic appointment
with someone that you want to go out with.
But you have a date.
This is something you have.
I have a date that night.
So this is actually a
very important part
because as you said, it's
a romantic appointment.
So if you have to go to the doctor and he's
not your boyfriend or anything like this,
you don't say, "I have
a date with the doctor.
" No, you say, "I have an
appointment with the doctor.
" Okay.
A romantic, you say, "Ooh, I want to get
my hair done because I have a date tonight.
" Right.
I have a date.
I want to look nice for my date.
Okay.
And then he goes on
to explain that this date
that he has is with a girl
that he has been chatting with.
Okay.
So the verb here is to chat with chat.
Chat just means to talk
to talk to, but in internet
terms, chat with means
to talk to on the internet.
So maybe you use a program like MSN or
Google G-Chat to talk to somebody online.
That's called chatting.
That's right.
So I think everyone has
done this at one point
or another when you
are online chatting via
MSN messenger or
any of these chat clients.
So very, very calming thing.
But remember to add the chat
with, I am chatting with my friends.
Yeah.
I don't like to chat with
people while I'm at work.
Exactly.
And now this guy explained
about the website match.
com and he said that he
signed up for this website.
Okay.
Another really key verb when
you're talking about internet things.
So for example, if you
want to come to China,
if you want to come to English
pod, you can sign up for a free trial.
That means provide your information.
Right.
Start to use.
That's right.
So it applies for things
online and offline.
For example, in the real world or offline,
you can sign up for a cooking class.
That's right.
Or last week, I signed up for a
dance class so I can learn how to dance.
Very good.
Okay.
And then to finish
off the guy explained
that he's tired of meeting people at bars
or that his friends set up dates for him.
Okay.
So he doesn't like to
be set up to be set up.
Remember that B to be set up, I
mean someone else is doing this to you.
So Marco, I want to set
you up with my friend.
That means I want to take you and
my friend and make you have a date.
Right.
Exactly.
So this is exactly
what it means to set
someone up or to be set up is to have
them go on a date with someone else.
All right.
So I don't like to be set up because I like
to know the person I will have a date with
before we go out, but when you're set up,
someone else makes the decision for you.
So it's a little bit difficult.
That's right.
Okay.
So a lot of interesting things here.
Why don't we take a look at our dialogue
one last time and we'll be right back.
Do you want to hang out tomorrow?
Oh, I can't have a date.
Really?
Wow.
With who?
This girl I've been chatting with
for the past couple of months.
She's really cool and she's
driving over here this weekend.
Wait a minute.
You mean you met her online?
Yeah.
I send up for a website
called match.com and it's great.
You fill in all your
details and preferences
like if you are a smoker
or if you have any
pets, then you find
people that have similar
characteristics and you
can email them or chat.
That's kind of weird.
What if she's a psycho
or something like that?
That's the same as meeting people anywhere
and dating them, I'm just tired of going to
bars and being set up
for dates by my friends.
I think this is a really cool alternative,
especially if you are a bit shy.
I guess it does seem logical.
I'll have to check it out.
All right.
So talking about
setting up, but this is
another word that
comes to mind when your
friend set you up for
a date is a blind date.
Okay.
So a blind date is not a
date with two blind people.
Right.
Is a date that you go to when you don't
know who the other person is before you go?
That's right.
So for example, my friend's mother
loves to set people up on blind dates.
All right.
She's a match maker.
She makes these, makes couples.
And so she will call
one person and call the
other person and then
she'll make them have a date.
She sets them up and
then they have this date,
a blind date, a blind
date, that's right.
And actually, what
you're doing with this
technology now that you
can use a website to find
and meet people who are also
looking for romance, it's very interesting.
It's very modern, obviously, because
now we have the technology to do it.
And many people actually have very successful
or very great love stories of how they
met online, chatting
or while playing a video
game online or many
different things like this.
Well, the thing that I like about it,
and I have to say I've never done it.
What I like from hearing about it is
that like mass.com, you save a lot of time.
It seems that way.
Because you get to tell the person, hey, I
don't want, I don't like people who smoke,
I don't like, who have pets, but I
really like people who play video games.
And so you find people
who are like that and
then you can, you know,
get to know that person
better.
But I think it's hard when
you're going on dates,
especially, you know, your
friends, they set you up.
And you have nothing in common.
You have no interests
that are in common and
that can, that can
be really frustrating.
So it seems like online dating is a new
type of efficient way of dating because you
preliminary already
filter out everyone or
everything that you
don't like about a person,
and you find someone that
has your same or similar likes.
So it, but that's, that's
modern day, right?
That's right.
A lot of people I now have dated using these
websites and have been very successful.
Really.
It's been married.
Amazing.
So actually, this is a great thing.
Let us know if you
have any friend who's
found their significant
other husband or wife
via online dating or if you've tried it,
maybe you can let us know how it is.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
Don't forget to sign up if you don't
have an account and we'll see you there.
All right.
Bye guys.
Bye.